Benjamin Cato

With over a decade of experience in **front-end development**, I thrive on infusing projects with creativity and passion. I excel in collaborative environments and approach each project as a work of art, taking pride in my role as the artist.

402 Bridgepoint Ln.
Woodstock, GA 30189
(404) 374-1696
bcato3000@gmail.com
bcato3000.github.io/portfolio

EXPERIENCE

Inspire Brands, Atlanta — *UI engineer*

June 2024 -Present

- Front-end development with React and Next JS/TS for white label applications across brands
- Liaison between UX design and developers
- HTML5 / CSS3 / Sass / JS and TypeScript

Capstone Logistics, Atlanta — *Lead front-end developer*

Jan 2024 - June 2024

- Front-end and limited back-end web development for Vue 3 JS/TS SPA for logistics and dispatching applications
- Team lead for our web portal team
- Liaison between UX design and developers
- HTML5 / CSS3 / Sass / JS and TypeScript
- Mentor of junior front-end devs

Whereoware, Atlanta — Senior front-end developer

May 2023 - October 2023

- Expertise in creating modular components via React and Storybook (via TypeScript)
- Optimizing user interfaces for Optimizely & Sitecore (CMS)
- Involved with front-end code review of PRs
- Expertise in responsive web development (mobile devices and desktop) and pixel-perfect UI
- Team lead for multiple front-end projects
- Composition breakdown of components
- AA SEO optimization
- HTML5 / CSS3 / Sass / JS and TypeScript
- Mentor of junior front-end devs
- Development for companies such as: Vector and Connectwise

SKILLS (# of years)

HTML5 (10+)

CSS3 (10+)

Sass (10+)

JavaScript (10+)

jQuery (7)

TypeScript (4)

Storybook (4)

RESTful APIs (5)

SPAs (React/Vue) (4)

Node (5)

Web components (1)

Responsive design/dev (10+)

Cross-browser (10+)

Accessibility standards (8)

Git (8)

UX (10)

Adobe creative suite (7)

Sketch App (5)

Figma (4)

Agile / Scrum (10+)

Client-facing contributor (8)

PC Windows (10+)

Mac iOS (10+)

BrainJocks / Perficient, Alpharetta — Lead front-end developer

December 2021 - May 2023

- Returned to Brainjocks / Perficient
- Created SPAs via React for large-scale CMS platforms (Sitecore 8 & 9 / Optimizely)
- Modular components and applications via React and Storybook (via TypeScript)
- Responsive web development expertise (mobile devices and desktop)
- AA & AAA SEO optimization
- HTML5 / CSS3 / Sass / LESS and JS
- Design liaison
- Mentor of junior front-end devs
- Client-facing and development for clients such as: Cooks Children's Hospital,
 Publix, and Sage

Fleetcor, Atlanta — Senior front-end developer

August 2020 - December 2021

- Front-end development fintech
- Collaborated with UI / UX designers and bridged the gap between graphical representations and technical implementation via vanilla JS, D3 Js for graphical interface
- Creator of global component library for enterprise purposes
- Provided front-end expertise for HTML / CSS / JS Unit-tests via Jest

BrainJocks / Perficient, Alpharetta — Lead front-end developer

April 2013 - July 2020

- Created SPAs via React for large-scale CMS platforms (Sitecore, Optimizely)
- Modular components and applications via React and Storybook (via TypeScript)
- Responsive web development expertise (mobile devices and desktop)
- AA SEO optimization
- HTML5 / CSS3 / Sass / LESS / JS
- Design liaison
- UI instructor of SCORE (our customized front-end software)
- Mentor of junior front-end devs
- Client-facing and development for clients such as: P&G, Honeywell, Central Garden & Pet, Marcus & Millichap, and Pergo

EDUCATION

The Creative Circus, Atlanta — Interactive Development

Graduate: 2012 - 2013

Chattahoochee Tech, Acworth — Computer Science

Graduate 2001 - 2003

Kennesaw State University, Kennesaw — Computer Science